// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: " which one the following defines as one-to-one function?",
    answer: "f={(x,y): y= 3x - 1}",
    options: [
      "f={(x,y): y=x^2 + 1}",
      "f={(x,y): y is father of X}",
      "f={(x,y): x is sister of y}",
      "f={(x,y): y= 3x - 1}"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Given two vector u=(1,3) and v=(-3,5) in the plane. then 6u + 2v is equal to",
    answer: "(0,28)",
    options: [
      " (2,28)",
      "(0,28)",
      "(0,18)",
      "(3,3)"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following represents the vector (3, -5, 7) in the space using the standard unit vectors i, j and k ? ?",
    answer:  "3i - 5j + 7k",
    options: [
      "3i - 5j + 7k",
      "3i - 5j - 7k",
      "-3i - 5j - 7k",
      "3i + 5j + 7k"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "which one of the following is the scalar(dot) product of the vectors (2,-4,6) and (-2,-1,0) ?",
    answer:  "0",
    options: [
      "8",
      "6",
      "0",
      "-8"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: " what is the modulus of th complex number -6 + 8i ?",
    answer: "10",
    options: [
      "10",
      "8",
      "5",
      "2"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "what is the magnitude of the vector whose initial point is at (1,-3) and terminal point is at (4, 1) ? ",
    answer:  "5",
    options: [
      "1",
      "4",
      "5",
      "6 "
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "the inverse of the function y= 3x-5 is equal to ",
    answer: "y= (x+5)/3",
    options: [
      "y= (x-5)/3",
      "y=-5x+3",
      "y= (x+5)/3",
      "y= (x+3)/5"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "the equation of a line is given by 3x-2y+6=0. then which of the following is true about the line? ",
    answer:"its slope is 3/2 ",
    options: [
      "(2,5) lies on the line",
      "its x-intercept is 2 ",
      "its y-intercept is -3 ",
      "its slope is 3/2 "
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "the angle of elevation of the top of tree is found to be 60 degree as measured from a point on a level ground. what is the height of the tree if the angle of elevation of a point on the tree that is 8m below the top is 30 degree measured from the same point on the ground? ",
    answer: "12 m ",
    options: [
      "14 m ",
      "12 m ",
      "8 m ",
      "4 m "
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "the equation of a circle is given by (x-3)^2 + (y+2)^2 =9 what are the center and radius of the circle respectively? ",
    answer: " (3, -2) and 3 ",
    options: [
      " (3, -2) and 3 ",
      "(3, 2) and 9 ",
      "(3, 2) and 3",
      "(3, -2) and 9"
    ]
  },






];